<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Quora | HuoJu's weblog]]></title>
  <link href="http://huoju.devep.net/blog/categories/quora/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://huoju.devep.net/"/>
  <updated>2012-02-01T20:11:08+08:00</updated>
  <id>http://huoju.devep.net/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Huo Ju]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Oracle Bones: it might be helpful to understand today's china]]></title>
    <link href="http://huoju.devep.net/blog/2011/12/22/oracle-bones/"/>
    <updated>2011-12-22T23:27:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://huoju.devep.net/blog/2011/12/22/oracle-bones</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Quora: <a href="http://www.quora.com/What-books-are-helpful-in-understanding-the-current-politics-economics-and-technology-of-China">What books are helpful in understanding the current politics, economics and technology of China?</a></p>

<p>My answer:</p>

<p>I highly recommend <em><a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0060826592/ref=as_li_tf_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=virushuotechb-20&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325&amp;creativeASIN=0060826592">Oracle Bones</a></em> to you. It's the best book about china written by a western author I have ever seen.</p>

<p>The author, Peter Hessler used to live in china for many years and work for <em>Wall Street Journal</em>. It's an important period for china in the last thirty years when he lived in china. Many historical events both significant to china and US happened during 1999-2004 whose influence still continues into the present.</p>

<p>For example:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/U.S._bombing_of_the_Chinese_embassy_in_Belgrade">U.S. Bombing of the Chinese embassy in Belgrade</a>, 1999</li>
<li>The 10th anniversary of<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tiananmen_Square_protests_of_1989"> June Fourth Incident</a>, 1999</li>
<li><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hainan_Island_incident">Hainan Island incident</a>, 2001<br/>
911 attacks, 2001</li>
<li>President Bush Speaks at Tsinghua University, 2002
...</li>
</ul>


<p>Moreover, the author writes much about the common Chinese individuals' life relating to economics, such as:</p>

<ul>
<li>Willy, Peter's student who cames from Sichuan province, worked as a teacher in Wenzhou. (this city famous at cheap small commodities)</li>
<li>Emily, who worked in Shenzhen. (this city is the forefront of reform and opening up)
...</li>
</ul>


<p>And the author introduced many historical details about china history, culture, archeology, oracle bones and the suffering of some scholars in related fields during the Cultural Revolution.</p>

<p>You would know more about china which be in the past when you finished this book, it might be helpful to understand today's china.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0060826592">Oracle Bones: A Journey Through Time in China</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[It's never too late to start studing anything]]></title>
    <link href="http://huoju.devep.net/blog/2011/12/21/its-never-too-late-to-start-studing-anything/"/>
    <updated>2011-12-21T01:01:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://huoju.devep.net/blog/2011/12/21/its-never-too-late-to-start-studing-anything</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Quora question: <a href="http://www.quora.com/Is-twenty-six-too-old-to-become-a-developer">Is twenty-six too old to become a developer?</a></p>

<p>My answer:</p>

<p>The simple answer is "Absolutely not".</p>

<p>The complex answer, I want to share you a real story which is happening around me.</p>

<p>Several years ago I knew a 26-years-old guy who works as a market commissioner. Market commissiner is a boring and low-paying job in china. One day he asked me weather he is too old to study programming? He wanted to change his job because programmer is a decent work with higher incoming. "Sure, no problem", I answered. And I suggested he start from PHP language, a skill shortages specific to Chinese Internet companies. He accepted my advice and started reading PHP documents and studying by following the official tutorial.</p>

<p>He did find a coding job after 4 months, although the salary was’t very high, however, he becomed a programmer! He was glad and worked hard to improve his technical level, then, he got another job at a bigger company after half a year. Then just after one year later, another large company asked him to join them. Today he is really a good programmer. Can you imageine that he started from a market commissioner?</p>

<p>Yes, programming is not easy.A good programmer has to learn a lot, for example: mathematic, arithmetic, data structure, OS... and master several programming languages. But this is not the the full story. The aim of programming is solving problem. In many cases, the problems that you are facing don’t appear to be so difficult, which can be solved easily and don’t need so much knowledge and skill. So if you do not remain satisfied with this, you would continue to improve through the continuous learning and experience.</p>

<p>This is an age when people live far longer, we all have opportunity to keep learning something new for decades, and get what you want one day. I believe it's never too late to start studing anything.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
